<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>network analysis | Yann Ryan</title>
    <link>https://yann-ryan.github.io/tag/network-analysis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://yann-ryan.github.io/tag/network-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>network analysis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://yann-ryan.github.io/media/icon_hu64ff187e2bf2a73fa3d6999beaf50dc7_9262_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>network analysis</title>
      <link>https://yann-ryan.github.io/tag/network-analysis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short Guide to Historical Newspaper Data, Using R</title>
      <link>https://yann-ryan.github.io/project/newspaper_data_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yann-ryan.github.io/project/newspaper_data_book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018 and 2019 I worked at the British Library as a Curator of Newspaper Data. It was an experimental position, conceived on the premise that the data generated by newspaper digitisation projects, in this case the Heritage Made Digital project, deserves its own curatorial role and set of practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an fun time to work on such a project. While the large-scale analysis of newspaper data by historians is no longer in its infancy, it’s still probably in an adolescence, and it was exciting working within an evolving discipline, one which is developing its own set of practices, understanding where and how its bias works and the implications this might have, and generally moving from a sense of naive optimism to a practice which is more academically and mathematically rigorous and self-reflective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book aims to give basic handbook for those who would like to dip their toes into big data analysis but don’t know where to begin. It takes advantage of the fact that for the first time, newspaper data from British Library is available to download, in bulk and for free. It uses some of that data, walking through the process from its download to running basic DH analyses: word frequencies, sentiment analysis, topic modelling and text reuse detection. It also introduces some mapping techniques, again using a dataset produced and made available by the British Library: a metadata list of the newspaper collection, which we hope will be of use to a wide variety of researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Measure of the Archive: The Robustness of Network Analysis in Early Modern Correspondence</title>
      <link>https://yann-ryan.github.io/publication/ca_robustness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yann-ryan.github.io/publication/ca_robustness/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peripatetic Networks, The Impact of Mobility on an Early Modern Correspondence Network</title>
      <link>https://yann-ryan.github.io/talk/peripatetic-networks-the-impact-of-mobility-on-an-early-modern-correspondence-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yann-ryan.github.io/talk/peripatetic-networks-the-impact-of-mobility-on-an-early-modern-correspondence-network/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distant Reading Large Correspondence Archives Using Networks</title>
      <link>https://yann-ryan.github.io/talk/distant-reading-large-correspondence-archives-using-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yann-ryan.github.io/talk/distant-reading-large-correspondence-archives-using-networks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Papers Visual Search</title>
      <link>https://yann-ryan.github.io/project/visual-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yann-ryan.github.io/project/visual-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This application is designed as a way to make searching through a very large mass of documents (the 170,000 letters of the Stuart State Papers) for relevant results easier. Users can enter a keyword in the search bar, which displays a small bar chart of &amp;lsquo;hits&amp;rsquo; for that term per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking and dragging on a year range on that bar chart displays geographic hits, for that period, in a miniature map in another window. Finally, the user draws a shape (either a polygon or rectangle) on the map, which displays all letters with the selected parameters as a network diagram in the main viewing pane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking on an &amp;lsquo;edge&amp;rsquo; (a line denoting a letter sent between two individuals) displays all the relevant letters in date order, along with their brief descriptions from the Calendars of State Papers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Clusters Browser</title>
      <link>https://yann-ryan.github.io/project/temporal-clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yann-ryan.github.io/project/temporal-clusters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This application was built as a UI layer on top of the results of an algorithm developed by Sebastian Ahnert to detect the presence of short-term temporal clusters in network data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application displays all of the detected clusters on an interactive timeline, built using R and Plotly. Clicking on a cluster in the timeline displays an interactive network diagram in a separate pane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application also lists the letters belonging to the cluster in order, alongside links to the relevant manuscript images in State Papers Online (if these are available internally). It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to filter the timeline by keyword or individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Screen%20Shot%202021-04-26%20at%2011.15.06.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Screen%20Shot%202021-04-26%20at%2011.15.26.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
